RESUME



Dr. Yan Hong

 $Double-appointed \ Associate \ Professor \ at \ the \ Deaprtment \ of \ Fashion \ Design \ \& \ Engineering \ and \ Interdiscipnary \ College, Soochow \ University$

Membership of SMDTex (Sustainable Management & Design of Textile, European Comission)

Talents of the International Postdoctoral Exchange Fellowship Program (Ministry of Education of PRC)

"Young Talent Support Project" Awarded by the China Association for Science and Technology

Member of Manufacturing Innovation & Entrepreneurship Working Committee of China Technology Entrepreneurship Association

Date of Birth: October 12th, 1990

Email: hongyan@suda.edu.cn

Language: Mandarin, English, French (Basic), Romanian (Basic), Cantonese (Basic)

Research Interest: Desgin Intelligence and Application

Education

2009 - 2013 Bachelor of Engineering in Fashion Design, Soochow University (Graduate with honor)

2013 - 2014 Master of Art in Fashion & Textile Design, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University

2014 - 2018 Joint Doctor of Psychology in Sustainable Design & Management in Fashion & Textile

Doctor of Psychology in Automation, École Nationale Supérieure des Arts et Industries Textiles

(ENSAIT), Université de Lille, France

Doctor of Psychology in Industrial Design, "Gheorghe Asachi" Technical University of Iasi, Romania

Doctor of Psychology in Fashion Design & Engineering, Soochow University, China

2018 - 2019 Post-doctor, National Laboratory of Textile (GEMTex), France

Professional Experience

2014-2016 Research Assistant, National Laboratory of Textile (GEMTex), France

2016-2018 Researcher, National Laboratory of Textile (GEMTex), France

2018 Till Now Associate Professor, Deaprtment of Clothing Science and Engineering, Soochow University

(Master Tutor, Joint doctoral supervisor, Program Leader of Fashion Design & Management)

Part-time Academic Experience

2022 Till Now Guest Editor, Sustainabilty (SCI & SSCI Journal)

2021 Till Now Member of the Editorial Board, Industria Textila (SCI Journal)

2021 Till Now Member of the Youth Editorial Board, Journal of Textile Research (El Journal), China

2018 Till Now MBA Tutor, Newton Business School

Industrial Experience

2014 Till Now Part-time Consultant, Carlin Trend Agency, France

2016 Till Now Branding Consultant, Dessilles, France

2017 Till Now Founder, Yannic Hong, France

Subjects Taught

MSc Artificial Intelligence for Fashion & Textile

BSc Foundational Fashion Design, Sustainable Design & Management for Fashion

Ready-to-Wear Design, Fashion Buying

HD General Introduction to Design Thinking, Foundational Fashion Design

Honorary Title

Passport Talent Maisons de Mode, National Passport Talent Program, France

Introduced Talent International Postdoctoral Exchange Fellowship Program (Ministry of Education of PRC), China

Supported Talent "Young Talent Support Project" Awarded by the China Association for Science and Technology

Leading Talent Leading Talents Program of Gusu District, Suzhou, China

Industrial Projects

- ManiForm Fashion Design Project (2014) in Shenzhen International Underwear Trade Show (PI)
 - Dessilles Branding Strategy & VI Design Project (2016), 25,641 Euro (PI)
- Dessilles Merger & Acquisition Project (2016), 384,615 Euro
- LD Couture Branding Strategy Project (2018), 100,000 CNY (PI)
 - Chanel Ancient Skirt (1927) Repair Project (2018), 12,000 Euro (PI)
- Martin Grant Branding Strategy & New Product Development Project (2019), 240,000 CNY (PI)
 - Coral Development of an Innovative Space for Sustainable Consumption-Urban Renewal Under the Logic of Industrial Economy (2019), 53,000 CNY (PI)
 - Oceanion Project of Sustainability Intergration with Branding & New Product Development Project (2020), 140,000 CNY (PI)
 - ZhengDa ZhengDa Knitting Fashion Space Design (2021), 300,000 CNY (PI)
 - DongLong Popular trend mining based on social network big data and its application in the development of lace products (2022), 500,000 CNY (PI)

Externally Granted Research Projects

- 2014 European Erusmus Munds Joint Doctoral Program, European Commission (100,000 Euro)
 Customized Garment Design System For Elderly People Or Persons With Physical Disabilities From Body Scan Data
- 2017 Maisons de Mode, National Design Talent Program, France (25,000 Euro/Year, PI)
 Development of A Sustainable Fashion Brand
- 2017 EU Horizontal Line 2020 Program, European Commission (3,760,000 Euro)

 A Knowledge-based business model for small series fashion products by integrating customized innovative services in big data environment (Fashion Big Data Business Model)
- 2018 United Fashion Exchange Program, European Commission (1,000 Euro, PI)
 Riga Fashion Week Project
- 2018 International Postdoctoral Exchange Fellowship Program (Ministry of Education of PRC), China Development of an Intelligent Knowledge-Based Personalized Garment Design Support System for People with Atypical Morphology (600,000 CNY, PI)
- 2019 Jiangsu Post-doctoral Research Grant Scheme, China (20,000 CNY, PI)
 Quantitative Analysis & Modeling of Fashion Design Knowledge Based on Case-Based Reasoning & Sensory
 Engineering
- 2019 National Science Foundation of China (240,000 CNY, PI)

 Quantitative Research on the Mechanism of Perceptual Cognition of Garment Style under Multiple Psychological Effects
- 2019 Chinese Post-doctoral Research Grant Scheme (100,000 CNY, PI)

 Quantitative Analysis & Modeling of Fashion Design Knowledge Based on Case-Based Reasoning & Sensory Engineering
- 2020 Scientific Research Project of Fiber Materials and Products for Emergency Protection and Public Safety, National Advanced Functional Fiber Innovation Center

 Research and development of MOFs based comfortable long-term filtering PP melt blown material and its application in personal protective equipment (200,000 CNY, PI)

Awards

- 2016 Best Paper Award, FLINS 2016
 - Selection & Application of Key Performance Indicators for Personalized Garment Design & Production Process Based On FANP
- 2017 Gold Price, EUROPEAN EXHIBITION OF CREATIVITY AND INNOVATION

 Customized garment design system for elderly people or persons with physical disabilities from body scan data
- 2017 Gold Price, National Institute of Inventics, Romania

 Customized garment design system for elderly people or persons with physical disabilities from body scan data

Publications First Autor/Corresponding Author Papers

- 1. Hong, Y., Zeng, X., Wang, Y., Bruniaux, P., & Chen, Y. (2018). CBCRS: An open case-based color recommendation system. Knowledge-Based Systems, 141, 113-128. (SCI—区TOP, IF: 8.038)
- 2. Y. Hong, T. Wu, X. Zeng, Y. Wang, W. Yang and Z. Pan. (2019). Knowledge-Based Open Performance Measurement System (KBO-PMS) for a Garment Product Development Process in Big Data Environment. IEEE Access, 7, 129910-129929. (SCI ☐ ▼ TOP, IF: 3.367)
- 3. Chen, L. L., Lou, L. Q., Liu, C. Y., & Hong, Y*. (2021). Color tunable luminescent cellulose acetate nanofibers functionalized by Cul-based complexes. Cellulose, 28(3), 1421-1430. (SCI

 ▼TOP, IF: 5.044)
- 4. Hong, Y.; Liu, C.; Cao, X.; Chen, Y.; Chen, Y.; Pan, Z. Process Evaluation of the Metal-Organic Frameworks for the Application of Personal Protective Equipment with Filtration Function. Polymers 2018, 10, 1386. (SCI≡⊠, IF: 4.329)
- 5. Hong, Y., Zeng, X., Bruniaux, P., & Liu, K. (2017). Interactive virtual try-on based three-dimensional garment block design for disabled people of scoliosis type. Textile Research Journal, 87(10), 1261-1274. (SCI K, IF: 1.82)
- 6. Hong, Y., Bruniaux, P., Zeng, X., Curteza, A., & Liu, K. (2018). Design and evaluation of personalized garment block for atypical morphology using the knowledge-supported virtual simulation method. Textile Research Journal, 88(15), 1721–1734. (SCI

 ▼, IF: 1.82)
- 7. Hong, Y., Zeng, X., Bruniaux, P., Chen, Y., & Zhang, X. (2018). Development of a new knowledge-based fabric recommendation system by integrating the collaborative design process and multi-criteria decision support. Textile Research Journal, 88(23), 2682–2698. (SCI \(\subseteq \), IF: 1.82)
- 8. Hong, Y., Zeng, X., Bruniaux, P., Curteza, A., Stelian, M., & Chen, Y. (2018). Garment opening position evaluation using kinesiological analysis of dressing activities: case study of physically disabled people with scoliosis (PDPS). Textile Research Journal, 88(20), 2303–2318. (SCI \(\subseteq\), IF: 1.82)
- 9. Zhang, J., Zeng, X., Dong, M., & Hong, Y*. (2021). Garment recommendation in an e-shopping environment by using a Markov Chain and Complex Network integrated method. Textile Research Journal, 00405175211021442. (SCI X, IF: 1.82)
- 10. Hong, Y., Bruniaux, P., Zeng, X., Liu, K., Curteza, A., & Chen, Y. (2018). Visual-simulation-based personalized garment block design method for physically disabled people with scoliosis (PDPS). Autex Research Journal, 18(1), 35-45. (SCI≡⊠, IF: 1.375) 11. Abtew, M. A., Kumari, A., Babu, A., & Hong, Y. (2020). Statistical analysis of standard allowed minute on sewing efficiency
- in apparel industry. Autex Research Journal, 20(4), 359-365. (SCI≡⊠, IF: 1.375)
- 12. Hong, Y., Bruniaux, P., Zeng, X., & Dong, M. (2017). Virtual reality-based collaborative design method for designing customized garment for disabled people with scoliosis. International Journal of Clothing Science and Technology, 29(2), 226-237. (SCI 四区, IF: 0.969)
- 13. Hong, Y., Zeng, X., Bruniaux, P., Liu, K., Chen Y., Framework of Consumer Perceived Value On Fashion Products For Female College Students In France. Industria Textila. 2018, 69(6), 495-501. (SCI四区, IF: 0.784)
- 14. Hong, Y., Zeng X, Bruniaux P, Liu K, Chen Y. Collaborative 3D-To-2D Tight-Fitting Garment Pattern Design Process for Scoliotic People. FIBRES & TEXTILES in Eastern Europe, 2017; 25, 5(125): 113-117. (SCI四区, IF: 1.045)
- 15. Hong, Y., Bruniaux, P., Zhang J., Liu K., Dong M., Chen Y. Application of 3D-TO-2D garment design for atypical morphology: a design case for physically disabled people with scoliosis. Industria Textila, 2018, 69(1), 59-64. (SCI四区, IF: 0.784)
- 16. Hong, Y., Chen, Y., Pan, ZJ., Chen, Y. A Conceptual Wearable Monitoring System for Physiological Indices and Clothing Microclimate Measurement. International Journal of Clothing Science and Technology, 29(2), 226-237. (SCI四区, IF: 0.969)
- 17. Ling, X., Hong, Y.*, & Pan, Z. (2020). Development of a dress design knowledge base (DDKB) based on sensory evaluation and fuzzy logic. International Journal of Clothing Science and Technology. **(SCI**四区, **IF: 0.969)**
- 18. Fang YU, Yan HONG. Development of A Hat Style Recognition System Based on Image Processing and Deep Learning. Industria Textila (Accepted). (SCI四区, IF: 0.784)
- 19. Abtew, M. A., Boussu, F., Bruniaux, P., & Hong, Y. (2021). Dynamic Impact Surface Damage Analysis of 3D Woven Para-Aramid Armour Panels Using NDI Technique. Polymers, 13(6), 877. (SCI三区, IF: 4.329)
- 20. Lili Chen, Yan Hong. Research on the Application of Collaborative Learning in the Practice Teaching of Garment 3D Virtual Fitting. Industria Textila (Accepted). (SCI四区, IF: 0.784)
- 21. Dai, X., Zeng, X., Liu, S., & **Hong, Y***. (2021). Is skin pressure in load carriage over-evaluated? Journal of Biomechanics, 130, 110854-110854. (**SCI** \sqsubseteq \boxtimes , **IF: 2.712**)
- 22. Xie, X., Hong, Y., Zeng, X., Dai, X., & Wagner, M. (2021). A Systematic Literature Review for the Recycling and Reuse of Wasted Clothing. Sustainability (2071-1050), 13(24). (SCI四区, IF: 3.251)

RESUME

01 Hong Kong Fashion Week Mechanical Evolution

A runway collection showed ir 2014 Spring & Summer Hong Kong Fashion Week, HK

02 China Silk Day Chinese Window

A runway collection showed ir 2010 Silk Day of China, Hangzhou, China

03 Shenzhen SUIF Fair Space Light

SUIF 2014' China Internationa Brand Underwear Fair, Shenzhen, May 2014

04 Nanjing Silk Museum Stereoscopic reflection

Invited to design a piece of Qipao to be exhibited in Nanjing Qipao Museum, Nanjing, China, May 2014

05 Riga Fashion Week Latvia

Invited to present a sustainable collection in Riga Fashion Week in October 2018

06 Paris Fashion WeekGare Saint Sauveur

Invited to release a collection of sustainable fashion design in 48H Maisons de Mode, Lille, France Sep. 2017

O7 FashionTech Day 2017CITE Tourcoing France

mytted to release a science&sustainable collection in FashionTech Day 2017 France, Oct, 2017























